# LIM, JING XUAN

JANELIA GRADUATE SCHOLAR JHU-JANELIA JOINT GRADUATE STUDENT limj2@janelia.hhmi.org

### **Profile**

I am a graduate student in the laboratory of Misha Ahrens where I work with the larval zebrafish. My research interest is in attaining a quantitative description of the neural computations underlying complex behavior and to understand the biophysical mechanisms that support them.

## Skills

# **Functional imaging**

Whole-brain light-sheet and twophoton calcium imaging of larval zebrafish fictively-behaving in a virtual reality environment. Voltage imaging of larval zebrafish using Voltron. Craniotomy, stereotaxic viral injection, fiber implantation in freely-moving mice.

## Data analysis

of whole-brain calcium imaging data. Development, simulation and analysis of multiscale models of biological neuronal networks in NEURON, using NetPyNE. Compartmental modeling of and in vivo calcium fiber photometry neuronal morphologies, generalized linear models for spiking activity and animal behavior.

# Electrophysiology

Distributed computation for analysis Rodent surgery and preparation of acute brain slices. In vitro patch clamp and field recordings. Biocytin labelling and post hoc recovery of cell morphologies using Neurolucida. Extracellular multiunit recordings and iontophoresis in head-fixed, non-anesthetized barn owls during the presentation of visual stimuli.

# Education

# Johns Hopkins University, United States of America

PhD Neuroscience 2017-present

Thesis advisor: Misha Ahrens (Janelia) and Dwight Bergles (Hopkins)

# University College London, United Kingdom

BSc Neuroscience 2012-2015

Classification: First Class Honours Thesis advisor: Beverley Clark

Thesis: Patch-clamp analysis of miniature synaptic currents in layer 5 cortical pyramidal cells of a Bardet-

Biedl Syndrome mouse model

Scholarship: National Science Scholarship (BS) from A\*STAR, Singapore

# Experience

# Dr Misha Ahrens :: Janelia Research Campus, HHMI

Janelia Graduate Scholar

Jun 2018-present

#### **State modulation of sensorimotor transformations**

Animals frequently switch between behavioral states in response to changes in their environment, in which they execute different sets of spontaneous and sensory-evoked behaviors. Using functional imaging methods, I aim to provide a computational description of how whole-brain information processing is altered during state changes. Harnessing the power of molecular techniques, I will also perform perturbation experiments in order to understand the underlying circuit and synaptic mechanisms.

# Prof Shreesh Mysore :: Johns Hopkins University

**Graduate Rotation Student** 

Jan 2018-May 2018

### Inactivation of reciprocal inhibition between Imc neurons in barn owls

Computational circuit models predict that reciprocal inhibition of inhibition between nucleus isthmi pars

magnocellularis (Imc) neurons might underlie flexible categorization in stimulus selection. With the aim of experimentally testing that hypothesis, I performed extracellular multiunit recordings from Imc neurons during iontophoresis of bicuculline, which was intended to be used to remove reciprocal inhibition, to check that the drug indeed removed all forms of inhibition.

# Prof Ernst Niebur :: Zanvyl Krieger Mind/Brain Institute, JHU

**Graduate Rotation Student** 

Aug 2017-Dec 2017

#### State-space models for gambling behaviour in monkeys

#### Co-supervisor: Dr Pierre Sacre, Institute of Computational Medicine

To better understand gambling behaviour in monkeys made to perform a multiattribute decision-making task, I constructed a generalised linear encoding model with present and past trial return and risk as covariates.

# Prof Fu Yu:: National University of Singapore

Research Officer Dec 2016-Jun 2017

#### Role of ventrolateral hypothalamic SST neurons in feeding behaviors

I developed a custom data visualization and acquisition software for fiber photometry and used it to investigate the effects of sleep-wake cycle on the activity of GCaMP-expressing ventrolateral hypothalamic SST neurons, whose activity controls feeding behaviour.

# Prof George Augustine :: Nanyang Technological University

Research Officer Jun 2015-Dec 2016

#### Reconstruction and simulation of the claustral network

### Co-supervisor: Prof William Lytton, SUNY Downstate Medical Center

I developed an *in silico* model of the claustrum with simplified integrate-and-fire spiking neurons tuned to intrinsic electrophysiological properties of different cell types and with connectivity based on optogenetic circuit-mapping data. I then performed a multitude of simulations in exploration of the dynamical features of the network. I presented this work at Society for Claustrum Research Annual Symposium 2016 and RIKEN Brain Science Institute Summer Program 2016.

# Dr Beverley Clark :: Wolfson Institute for Biomedical Research, UCL Undergraduate Thesis Project Researcher Sep 2014-Apr 2015

# Patch-clamp analysis of miniature postsynaptic currents in cortical pyramidal cells of a Bardet-Biedl Syndrome mouse model

#### Co-supervisor: Dr Christoph Schmidt-Hieber, Institut Pasteur

I performed whole-cell patch clamp on L5 cortical pyramidal neurons to investigate the functional changes in cortical wiring of the Bardet-Biedl Syndrome 5 knockout mouse, which were found to have decreased spine density. I also stained the neurons with biocytin and recovered their morphologies posthoc using Neurolucida in order to check for other structural deficits. This work culminated in the writing of a dissertation and a talk given to faculty and peers.

# Prof Sajikumar Sreedharan :: National University of Singapore Undergraduate Researcher Jul 2014-Sep 2014

#### Molecular events underlying hippocampal LTP

I performed field and patch-clamp recordings on organotypic slices to investigate the effects of various pharmacological agents on LTP and plasticity thresholds in CA1 pyramidal neurons. I also performed densitometric measurement of western blots using ImageJ to quantify the effects of LTP on protein phosphorylation levels.

# Dr Anne Rifkin-Graboi :: Singapore Institute for Clinical Sciences Undergraduate Researcher Jul 2013-Sep 2013

# $\underline{ \ \ } \ \, \underline{ \ \ }$

I performed extensive analysis on Lab-TAB (Laboratory Temperament Assessment Battery, for the assessment of behaviour, emotion and attention), EEG, eye-tracking and heart rate data.

#### Prof Adam Claridge-Chang :: Duke-NUS Graduate Medical School **Assistant Laboratory Officer** Jan 2012-Mar 2012

I performed laboratory technician duties such as keeping stocks, collecting virgins, setting up and scoring crosses and cooking fly food. I also learned how to perform brain dissection on the Drosophila melanogaster and various molecular biology techniques such as gene cloning, cDNA library building, RNA isolation, Q-PCR, miniprep and gel electrophoresis. Finally, I designed and set-up an optogenetics-enabled behavioural rig for the movement tracking of fruit flies for the investigation of anxiety circuits.

### **Awards**

## **Fellowships**

A\*STAR National Science Scholarship (BS) A\*STAR National Science Scholarship (PhD) 2012-2015 2017-2022

## Travel Scholarships

**RIKEN BSI Summer Program Travel Award** 

2016

## **Publications**

#### **Posters**

Jing Xuan Lim, Alireza Sheikhattar, Ziqiang Wei, Misha Ahrens (2018). Neural oscillations in sensorimotor processing. 28th annual Neuroscience Department and Neuroscience Training Program Retreat https://jingxlim.github.io/jhu18.pdf

Jing Xuan Lim, Salvador Dura-Bernal, George J. Augustine, William W. Lytton (2016). Computational models of claustrum subnetworks. Society for Claustrum Research Annual Symposium 2016 https://jingxlim.github.io/scr16.pdf

Jing Xuan Lim, Salvador Dura-Bernal, Rena Orman, Christoph Kayser, George J. Augustine, William W. Lytton (2016). Reconstruction and simulation of claustral microcircuitry based on optogenetic mapping. RIKEN Brain Science Institute Summer Program 2016. https://jingxlim.github.io/riken16.pdf

## **Theses**

Jing Xuan Lim and Beverley A. Clark (2015). Patch-clamp analysis of miniature synaptic currents in layer 5 cortical pyramidal cells of a Bardet-Biedl Syndrome mouse model. BSc dissertation, University College London. Ahttps://jingxlim.github.io/ucl15.pdf

## Language

Python	MATLAB	R
Bash	tcsh	HOC
NMDOL	Emacs Lisp	Markdown
Org Mode	HTML	CSS

### References

Misha Ahrens	George Augustine	Beverley Clark
PhD mentor	Research Supervisor	Thesis Supervisor
+1 571 209 4174	+65 6778 2012	+44 020 7679 6955
ahrensm@janelia.hhmi.org	george.augustine@ntu.edu.sg	b.clark@ucl.ac.uk